Guide to the Yale University Master of Fine Arts Theses In Graphic Design
Yale University Arts Library
Yale University Master of Fine Arts Theses in Graphic Design
1951-2016
AOB 33
Yale University Arts Library
75
(105 boxes)
The collection consists of over 600 individual Master of Fine Arts theses in graphic design from 1951 to the present.
Yale University. School of Art. Graphic Design Program
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the School of Art and the artists.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Multi-media works can only be viewed if a use copy is available.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1950, the Graphic Design Program at the Yale University School of Art is a well respected program training designers in technical and theoretical issues. The two-year course of study requires students to build a coherent, investigative, and experimental body of work. The program culminates in a thesis project in which the student creates a final document in support of a long-term, multi-faceted research project.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of over 600 individual theses from 1951 to the present. The theses are most often in book format, though some have more experimental formats. Individual records for the theses are also available in the library catalog.
Arrangement
Theses are listed in order by date, then in alphabetical order within each year.
Graphic arts; Theses; Yale University. School of Art
- Theses
  - Aspects of printing, 1951; Applegate, Asher Tunis; 3 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    One copy includes a presentation inscription by Applegate to Theodore Sizer as well as Sizer's embossed stamp of ownership.
  - Architecture and letter design "Brown Decades", 1952; Ives, Norman, 1923-1978 (Box 99)
  - Seventeen poems of fairyland / written and illustrated by Cornelia Schwarz., 1952; Luhn, Diana (Box 1)
    Diana Luhn earned a BFA in 1952. She completed the typography, type-setting, and letterpress printing for this book.
  - The graphic arts in the colleges., 1952; McCrillis, John O. C. (Box 1)
  - The relationship of the graphic designer to contemporary map design., 1952; Marmaras, Jack (Box 1)
    Jack Marmaras earned a BFA in 1952.
  - A master's thesis on color., 1953; Sillman, Sewell, 1924-1992 (Box 1)
    Sillman's thesis includes a dedication to Josef Albers.
  - Paper., 1954; Coulter, Sheilagh M., d. 2009 (Box 1)
    Sheilagh M. Coulter earned a BFA in 1954. "Paper" was part of her senior research project.
  - An historical survey of type founding: its implication and effect on the type designer., 1954; DeNatale, A. Richard (Box 1)
  - Sign controls., 1954; Doherty, Robert J., 1924- (Box 1)
  - Nineteenth century typography and printed advertising., 1954; Gentile, Gloria (Box 1)
    Includes 2 volumes. Volume 2 contains supplementary examples of typefaces from two nineteenth-century publications, The Port Folio and Godey's Lady's Book.
  - Photography without a camera., 1954; Cash, Barbara Luther, 1930- (Box 28)
  - Influence of Byzantine scholars and manuscripts on early Italian printers of Greek texts., 1954; Pappas, George N. (Box 22)
  - 26 tales of woe: an alphabet book by Tom Geismar., 1955; Geismar, Thomas H., 1932- (Box 1)
  - Examples of printmaking in 12 books: potato print, waxcut, mo-glu print, corrugated cardboard print, casein cut, linocut, wood cut, bean print, string print, cardboard print, paper print, drip print., 1955; Gorbaty, Norman (Box 1)
    Includes 12 volumes.
  - Printmaking with a spoon., 1955; Gorbaty, Norman (Box 32)
  - Newspaper design., 1955; Keshian, Harry Charles (Box 1)
    Includes 1 volume and 19 loose illustrations. Harry Charles Keshian earned a BFA in 1955.
  - A study of music printing., 1955; Morris, Robert C. (Box 1)
    Robert C. Morris earned a BFA in 1955.
  - A graphic approach to children's books., 1955; Kuskin, Karla (Karla Seidman Kuskin) (Box 1)
    Includes 2 volumes. Karla Seidman earned a BFA in 1955. Her senior research project was "A Graphic Approach to Children's Books," which included the printing of a small edition of an original children's book. This children's book, Roar and More, was later published by Harper in 1956.
  - The graphic artist and TV advertising., 1955; Sias, Morton W.; 2 (Box 2)
    The folder contains a version of Sias's thesis that was submitted in 1954. This copy has memoranda laid in by E. C. Cole and Charles H. Sawyer concerning its evaluation. The final version is dated May 2, 1955.
  - A story for children to read to their parents: the private revolt of Merton Burton., 1956; Antupit, Sam (Box 2)
  - Phototypesetting., 1956; Antupit, Sam (Box 33)
  - The Garamond Types I, II, III, IV., 1956; Parker, Mike, 1929-2014 (Box 28)
  - To a little girl, one year old, in a ruined fortress., 1956; Doggett, Jane Davis (Box 2)
  - Poster as an element of urban living., 1956; Granady (Box 2)
    Includes volume 2 only.
  - Eleven international dinners., 1956; Parker, Ann Russell; 2 (Box 2)
  - Photography for the painter., 1956; Resen, Kenneth Lawrence (Box 2)
  - An experiment in three dimensional design with children., 1956; Shertzer, Gerald (Box 2)
  - Orpheus., 1957; Boghosian, Varujan (Box 34)
  - Geometry of form, 1957; Cinamon, Gerald (Box 35)
  - Food packaging for the supermarket, 1957; Fletcher, Alan (Box 2)
  - An investigation into a method of design: New Haven Railroad Terminal, 1957; Hough, John "Jack" (Box 2)
  - An investigation into a method of design: New Haven Railroad Terminal, 1957; Hough, John "Jack" (Box 36)
  - Teaching column addition., 1957; Fleming, Guy (Box 2)
    Includes 47 slides.
  - An investigation of the visual possibilities of the photogram., 1957; Kramer, Burton (Box 28)
    Includes 2 volumes.
  - Le Signe: drame en cinq tableaux / Jacques Guicharnard., 1957; Kramer, Burton (Box 28)
  - Horizontals and verticals: a study of optical reversion in linear constructions, 1957; Kloszewski, Eugene P. (Box 2)
  - Lettering as an element in commercial signs., 1957; Robinson, Elton S.; 2 (Box 2)
  - Some aspects of modern bookbinding., 1957; Rolston, Michael Beier (Box 2)
    Includes 5 volumes.
  - The influence of modern painting upon recent American magazine advertising., 1957; Steiner, Henry (Box 37)
  - Passages from the Book of Isaiah, 1957; Van Dyk, James, 1930-2002 (Box 28)
  - Numerals, 1957; Pollock, Sylvia Winter, 1935- (Box 2)
  - Optical and physical mixtures, 1958; Bittleman, Arnold, 1933- (Box 22)
  - A trademark project, 1958; Szasz, Joel (Box 3)
  - Thesis on the perception of display typography., 1958; Hopkins, Joseph D., Jr. (Box 3)
    Includes 2 volumes (and 2 copies of volume 1).
  - Thesis on the perception of display typography, 1958; Hopkins, Joseph D., Jr. (Box 24)
  - Spacing the Garamond capitals for use on the protype machine., 1958; Korbet, Stephen (Box 48)
  - Design of a display type face, 1958; Van Inwegen, David (Box 3)
  - Design of a display type face, 1958; Van Inwegen, David (Box 39)
    Includes 2 copies of thesis and 26 woodblocks.
  - Evolution of English typography., 1958; Wolfe, Leonard (Box 22)
    Includes 4 volumes.
  - Thesis, 1959; Ferriter, Roger G. (Box 3)
  - Caslon "Display" letters, 1959; Gustavson, Martin (Box 28)
    Includes 2 parts.
  - The influence of handwriting on type design, 1959; Kner, Andrew (Box 40)
  - Visual aids for demonstrating and teaching calligraphy, 1959; Pontes, Crimilda, 1926-2000 (Box 3)
  - A symbol for the A & P stores, 1961; Herman, Sidney J. (Box 41)
  - Ballad of Sir Patrick Spens, 1961; Porter, E.C.; 2 (Box 3)
  - Variations on eight bars in a square., 1963; Arnholm, Ronald (Box 3)
  - Graphic design 60., 1963; Cimino, Michael (Box 3)
  - Directionals., 1963; Coleman, Thomas F. (Box 3)
  - On trademarks., 1963; Consuegra, David (Box 3)
  - Ensign - Beckford Company: development of a trademark., 1963; Dunne, Stephen (Box 3)
  - Mexican Indian design., 1963; Propper, Robert Adler (Box 3)
  - Basic design (article), 1964; Gregory, Albert (Box 3)
  - A Selection of Photographs of a Nez Perce Indian Family., 1964; Haling, George S. (Box 29)
  - Identification on buildings., 1964; Smart, Paul William (Box 3)
    General note
    See also entry under 1971.
  - Sans Serif Types., 1964; Westby, Gerald D. (Box 100)
    Includes 7 volumes.
  - Papermaking by hand., 1965; Atchley, Dana (Box 3)
    Includes 35 cards.
  - The Book of Els., 1965; Buzyna, Helen; 6 (Box 3)
  - Podium., 1965; Glickman, Franklin J. (Box 3)
  - Nine poems by e. e. cummings., 1965; Harley, Galen (Box 3)
  - Why the Negro Is Black., 1965; Katz, Joel; 3 (Box 3)
    See also entry under 1967.
  - Presenting information clearly in text books., 1965; Krueger, Theodore (Box 3)
  - A study of the reversible figure ground., 1965; Lipper, Carol (Box 22)
    Includes 3 parts.
  - A study of the reversible figure ground., 1965; Lipper, Carol (Box 42)
  - A poem from "The Rose" by William Butler Yeats: "To the Rose upon the rood of time.", 1965; McGinnis, Marcia; 2 (Box 3)
  - The experimentation and application of a design system., 1965; Noneman, J. D. (Box 43)
  - The A-Z book., 1965; Ockerse, Thomas; 2 (Box 22)
  - Cool Park and Ballylee., 1965; Parrish, Thomas D., Jr.; 7 (Box 4)
  - Poem from Lawrence Ferlinghetti's "A Coney Island of the Mind.", 1965; Pujol, Henry; 6 (Box 22)
  - A trademark for intercontinental hotels., 1965; Salchow, Gordon Robert (Box 22)
  - Sun is the source of light and warmth., 1965; Sarkar, Benoy; 5 (Box 4)
    See also entry under 1966.
  - Rubaiyat of Omar Kayyam., 1965 (Box 36)
  - Picasso on Picasso., 1965; Seefeld, Philip R.; 4 (Box 4)
  - Picasso on Picasso., 1965; Seefeld, Philip R. (Box 23)
  - Slaughter four., 1965; Slaughter, Carl C. (Box 22)
  - Slaughter four., 1965; Slaughter, Carl C. (Box 44)
  - Make a Shape, 1965; Weiss, Jack R.; 4 copies of "Empty Corridors" (Box 4)
  - Quotes, 1965; White, Kenneth L.; 3 copies of "Graphic Design Is..."; 5 copies of "Quotes" (Box 4)
  - Ladle rod rotten hut inner regional virgin., 1965; Yudell, Lynn D.; 5 (Box 4)
  - Albert Einstein hospital graphics., 1966; Akdag, Erdal (Box 23)
  - Untitled thesis: a series of serigraphs dealing with communication., 1966; Charney, Israel (Box 4)
  - Dream, 1966; Filzen, Joseph (Box 4)
  - Christmas impressions., 1966; Goldschmidt, Anthony, 1942-2014; 5 (Box 4)
  - An exhibition/environment structure., 1966; Congdon, Arthur (Box 23)
    Includes 2 volumes and 69 slides.
  - A Poster Series Illustrating the Theorems of Plane Geometry, 1966; Kirschenbaum, Esther (Box 4)
    Includes 4 slides.
  - A Corporate Design Program for Intercontinental Hotel Corporation, 1966; Libby, David (Box 23)
  - Designer's Guide to Offset, 1966; Pflugh, Gerald; 4 copies of "Small Book" (Box 4)
  - Universe., 1966; Sarkar, Benoy (Box 4)
    See also entry under 1965.
  - Calligraphy in India., 1966; Sarkar, Benoy (Box 23)
  - The development of a symbol., 1966; Smith, Laura J.; 3 (Box 4)
  - Exploiting the medium., 1966; Strong, Thomas; 2 (Box 23)
  - Type puns., 1966; Tevonian, Stephanie (Box 4)
  - Methods of typographic display., 1967; Chapman, Stephen (Box 4)
    See also entry under 1968.
  - Perspecta II, 1967; Godard, Keith; 5 (Box 5)
  - Yale University Charities Drive '66., 1967; Goldschmidt, Anthony, 1942-2014 (Box 5)
    Includes 21 slides.
  - Methods of typographic display., 1967; Ichiyama, Dennis (Box 5)
  - The cinematographic principle and the ideogram / by Sergei Eisenstein., 1967; Katz, Joel B. (Box 5)
  - The cinematographic principle and the ideogram / by Sergei Eisenstein., 1967; Katz, Joel B. (Box 53)
  - Typographic display., 1967; Marcus, Aaron (Box 5)
  - Seaside senior citizens housing., 1967; McGinnis, Marcia (Box 29)
    Includes 1 volume and 32 slides.
  - 9/10 times new roman., 1967; Nix, Robert; 3 (Box 5)
  - Variations/typographic display [Various Means of Typographic Display]., 1967; Pakay, Sedat (Box 5)
  - Film credits for Eugene Ionesco's Rhinoceros., 1967; Parrish, Thomas D., Jr. (Box 5)
  - Sabrina., 1967; Pujol, Henry (Box 5)
  - A symbol proposal Sterling Movies Incorporated., 1967; Seefeld, Philip Richard (Box 45)
  - Printed announcement and booklet for an architectural competition., 1967; Strong, Thomas (Box 5)
  - Gothic Ornament at Yale University., 1967; Weiss, Jack R. (Box 5)
  - Arches; photographic documentary of the Arches area in Elizabeth, New Jersey., 1967; White, Kenneth L. (Box 5)
  - Directional graphics., 1967; Yudell, Lynn D. (Box 5)
  - Connecticut furniture: seventeenth and eighteenth centuries., 1968; Channing, Laurence (Box 5)
  - Proportional experiments in sans-serif numerals., 1968; Chapman, Stephen D. (Box 5)
  - Abstract, representation and so forth..., 1968; Chrbachi, Samir; 2 (Box 5)
  - Gestalt laws of organization and preceptual forms and its application in the design of Japanese "Mon.", 1968; Ichiyama, Dennis (Box 5)
  - Early forms of numerals., 1968; Marcus, Aaron (Box 5)
  - Figures in a circle., 1968; Michel, Bruce (Box 5)
  - Italic type: its history, form and use., 1968; Morin, Thomas D. (Thomas Dennis), 1944- (Box 5)
  - The "Hypnerotomachia Poliphili" of 1499 and The "Discours du Songe de Poliphile" of 1546., 1968; Purvis, Alston (Box 23)
  - I Wish I Knew How It Would Feel To Be Free, 1968; Rosen, Peter (Box 6)
  - Renaissance interpretation of the Roman inscriptional capitals., 1968; Scharrenbroich, Ingo (Box 23)
  - Comprehensive perceptual communication., 1969; Creekmore, Wayne (Box 6)
  - Investigations into experimental animation., 1969; Mouris, Francis P. (Box 6)
  - [Film making]., 1969; Quraeshi, Samina (Box 6)
  - Developmental drawing., 1969; Rose, Michael David (Box 6)
  - Sounds and silences., 1969; Schlaifer, Peter (Box 6)
  - Experiments in animation., 1969; Strawbridge, John III (Box 6)
  - Three poems., 1969; Tilbury, David (Box 6)
  - Supergraphics., 1969; Wagner, Martha Poole (Box 6)
    Includes 20 slides.
  - Subway sign system., 1970; Casselman, Louise (Box 6)
  - [Drawings] Eye magazine, no.3., 1970; Demiryurek, Fahrettin (Box 6)
  - On desiging "Formations" an animated film of drawings., 1970; Garland, Nathan (Box 6)
  - Buddhism in Thailand., 1970; Garvin, Philip (Box 53)
  - The animation of drawn image functioning in a photographic world., 1970; Goldberger, Susan June (Box 6)
  - One way., 1970; Jackson, Reginald (Box 6)
  - Demian and Cat's Cradle: an experiment in film titling., 1970; Lamont, Carolyn (Box 6)
  - Two widowers., 1970; Simmons, Marvin Howard (Box 23)
  - Photography and printmaking., 1970; Wadden, Douglas J. (Box 6)
  - Vignettes., 1970; White, Peter (Box 6)
  - A proposal for a new information series at Yale University., 1971; Fleck, Anna Lou (Box 6)
  - Shapes., 1971; Kalish, Nicki; 4 copies of "things things"; 3 copies of "shapes" (Box 23)
  - A study of the cube: how graphics may be applied to a three-dimensional form., 1971; Lionetti, Frank (Box 6)
  - Workbooks for school children., 1971; Olman, Maxine (Box 6)
  - Trimalchio in west egg., 1971; Schorr, David; 2 (Box 23)
  - Let's mix colors., 1971; Smart, Paul William (Box 6)
    See also entry under 1964.
  - A color system., 1972; Fletcher, Judith (Box 23)
  - Manual for the Boston Globe., 1972; Johnson, Catherine (Box 6)
  - Environmental graphics., 1972; Khosrovi, Azar (Box 6)
  - [Thesis]., 1972; Lewis, Adam (Box 23)
  - Thesis Project: Yale Co-op., 1972; Poellnitz, Nathan (Box 6)
  - Analysis of a problem in architectural graphics., 1972; Spiegelman, Marjorie (Box 42)
  - Designing a set of special symbols., 1973; Byers, Stephen B. (Box 6)
  - Color gradations., 1973; Forshey, Ann (Box 6)
    Includes 1 volume and 39 slides.
  - Calendar for 1974., 1973; Goodman, Anne (Box 46)
  - Color theory., 1973; Greenboam, R. (Box 6)
    Includes 53 slides.
  - Graphic design submission for a railway station renovation in Wallingford, Connecticut, 1972-3., 1973; Logowitz, Stephen (Box 6)
    Includes 25 slides.
  - Transformation., 1973; Moore, Joseph (Box 23)
  - 2 Poems., 1973; Silverman, Missy (Box 23)
  - Erich Becker, 1973; Trudeau, G. B., 1948- (Box 76)
  - Structured space as product of form., 1974; Berggren, Dorothea Louise (Box 6)
  - The Kashmere shawl., 1974; Godlewski, Josef (Box 6)
  - Elements., 1974; Keating, Kerin (Box 23)
  - The applicability of a grid as a tool for teaching beginning design students., 1974; Salter, Peter (Box 6)
  - Identity crisis / by Christopher Durang., 1975; Garn, Aimée; 2 (Box 6)
  - Of the strife betwixt Grendel and Beowulf., 1975; Emlen, Katherine (Box 33)
  - Blowsabella., 1975; Geringer, Laura; 2 (Box 6)
  - Bembelman's bakery., 1975; Green, Melinda (Box 6)
  - Computer manipulated letterforms., 1975; Keith, Christopher (Box 7)
  - Diagramming urban transit systems., 1975; Laundy, Peter (Box 23)
    Includes 1 volume and 7 slides.
  - El-Ksiba, Morocco., 1975; Leger, Jacqueline (Box 7)
  - The history of proportion and Le Corbusier's Modulor., 1975; Wolfson, Lawrence (Box 24)
  - Music and typgraphy: parallelism of compositional development., 1976; Armstrong, Frank (Box 7)
    See also entry under 1978.
  - Hand book., 1976; Craig, Derry Noyes (Box 24)
  - Stars - Wall Chart., 1976; Fernandez, Oscar (Box 47)
  - Exterior identity program for the Yale University collection of musical instruments., 1976; Gibson, Charles (Box 38)
  - Food: a book about nutrition for children., 1976; Hofmann, Paula (Box 7)
  - The physical design and adornment of Chinese books., 1976; Koo, Manyee (Box 28)
  - Behind it all., 1976; Lauria, Jo (Box 7)
  - Cocalage., 1976; Schnipper, Steven (Box 49)
  - Excerpts; The function of reason., 1976; Whitehead, A. N. (Box 7)
  - Defining the terminology of symbol signs for use by the Graphic Designer., 1977; Ackley, Mark W. (Box 7)
  - Linguistics typography; an investigation of interdisciplinary application., 1977; Clementino, Ann (Box 7)
  - Preservation and transformation: a documentation of two painters: Howard Lee Wiess Richard Sheehan., 1977; Flanders, Marybeth (Box 24)
  - Beware the groons / Robert Jensen, designer., 1977; Hutchins, Patrick; 2 (Box 7)
  - Chinese characters: pictures to symbol., 1977; Kao, Grace (Box 7)
  - The painted environment., 1977; Morton, Margaret Lewin, d. 1823 (Box 7)
  - The type design of Morris Denton notes toward a revisionist history., 1977; Overmyer, Dwayne (Box 7)
  - Visualize Stravinsky: a sequential composition based on the Octet for Wind Instruments., 1977; Zender, Mike (Box 7)
  - Visual forms and sounds., 1978; Armstrong, Frank (Box 34)
    See also entry under 1976.
  - The catalogue problem: a workbook for designers and curators., 1978; Buie, Sarah Duncan (Box 7)
  - Spelling and the Shaw alphabet., 1978; Ferrari, Stephen (Box 7)
  - Proportion: an introduction., 1978; Humphrey, Heidi (Box 7)
  - Diagrammatic representation of overlapping activities., 1978; Katalan, Jak (Box 50)
  - Life that works., 1978; Lazin, Allysia (Box 7)
  - From Ox to A., 1978; Nowroozi, Akefeh K. (Box 7)
  - Graphic presentation of statistical data at the United States Census Bureau: 1870-1970., 1978; Reidhaar, James W. (Box 7)
  - Typesetting and its effect on letterform., 1978; Smiley, Deborah (Box 7)
  - Vision and communication., 1978; Winkler, Ellen K. (Box 7)
    Includse 2 parts.
  - Paper., 1979; Baker, Jan (Box 7)
  - Survey of Cape Cod's Vernacular Roadside Signs., 1979; Gebhard, T. (Box 24)
    Includse 2 volumes.
  - Symbol Redesign for the deparment of transportation., 1979; Gibson, Kurt; 2 (Box 7)
  - Reproducing photographs., 1979; Korostoff, Jill (Box 7)
  - The livre d'Artiste: a brief history: A tail of two tails., 1979; Meisel, Paul (Box 29)
  - Design and film: a survey of influences between the two media in Europe, 1918-1936., 1979; Rahman, Ram (Box 29)
  - Norman Seaton Ives., 1979; Severtson, Johan (Box 7)
  - Whalley Avenue A visual documentation of a short trip through an urban landscape., 1979; Shakespear, George (Box 36)
  - Translating musical events into visual imagery., 1979; Skolos, Nancy (Box 7)
  - Nsibidi and Vai: a survey of two indigenous West African scripts., 1979; Spence, Muneera Umedaly (Box 24)
  - Graphic design and photography resources at Yale University., 1979; Stewart, Ann; 2 (Box 29)
  - The effect of environmental factors on color a prosped course., 1979; Szabo, Robert F. (Box 24)
  - Concerning the spiritual in art., 1979; Yang, Larry (Box 7)
  - A chronology of coptic art and culture: Coptic Art and culture., 1980; Ballance, Georgette Parkas (Box 29)
  - The small private press New England 1979., 1980; Cash, Barbara, 1930- (Box 29)
  - Drawing as process., 1980; Dugdale, Juanita (Box 7)
  - Experiments in form and color., 1980; Elkin, Gregory (Box 29)
  - Graphic design; documentary chronology of developments in the Graphic Arts in the United States, 1865-1978., 1980; Gibson, David (Box 7)
  - Semiotics: an approach to the communication process., 1980; Gilliatt, Steven (Box 7)
  - Élan: a study in magazine design., 1980; Gorbaty, Lisa (Box 7)
  - Type and photographs: a synthesis., 1980; Johnson, Peter W. (Box 7)
  - [An Elizabethan Bookseller's Collection of Anonymous Essays and Discourses], 1980; Kendrick, Marvin (Box 8)
  - Exploring verbal puns, visual puns and other forms of word play and picture play., 1980; Kince, Elvin Elias Lee (Box 8)
  - Drawing as a mode for thinking., 1980; Larrabee, Benjamin Rood (Box 8)
  - Versations; a setting for eight conversations., 1980; Lehrer, Warren (Box 33)
  - Banners: history, design and fabrication., 1980; Woodard, Sylvia (Box 8)
  - The graphic of protest., 1981; Bernstein, Amy (Box 24)
  - Graphic design landmarks 1880-1980 in a cultural and historical context., 1981; Chesnut, Anne G. (Box 8)
  - Semiotics and the preoperational child: education against overpopulation., 1981; Debs, Claude F. (Box 8)
  - Modern typgraphy: roots and influences., 1981; Fountain, Jeanne (Box 8)
  - The generic corporate symbol., 1981; Harp, Douglas G. (Box 8)
  - Decoration as identity., 1981; Helfman, Ilisha (Box 24)
  - The line: a focus on the tools that create it., 1981; Lepley, Thom (Box 8)
  - A graphic interpretation of selected images from the mythology of the Taino culture of Puerto Rico., 1981; Lopez-Bonilla, Juan Pablo (Box 51)
  - The transformation of face and mask., 1981; Mann, Alison S. (Box 8)
  - Typography: the painter's role., 1981; Mendez, Lleana (Box 8)
  - Mechanization and expression: the establishment of the conventions of photography in design., 1981; Sudick, Barbara (Box 8)
  - Typography as pictorial image., 1981; Williams, Kristie Smith (Box 8)
  - The development of typographic layout in the twentieth century., 1981; Woodworth, Bradford (Box 8)
  - A study of the semantics of trademarks., 1982; Bachman, Thomas H. (Box 8)
  - Type:., 1982; Cossutta, Renée (Box 8)
  - Designers & type: preferences, criteria, observations., 1982; Cundy, David (Box 8)
  - Form in information., 1982; Fried, Geoffry (Box 8)
  - A chronology of Japanese books and publishing: 1600-1750., 1982; Harakawa, Ann (Box 8)
  - Robert Brownjohn: conceptual design., 1982; Homans, Katy; 2 (Box 8)
  - Underground renovation: a proposal for the 66th Street Subway Station., 1982; Hooykaas, Gerben (Box 8)
  - And in the middle you see., 1982; Jaffe, Holly (Box 52)
  - Ambiquity and scale., 1982; Johnson, Carrie (Box 24)
  - Luncheon date with Jackie O., 1982; Kinneary, Robert (Box 8)
  - Forms and meanings of the arrow., 1982; Korbet, Stephen (Box 29)
  - Symbol & sign: African imagery in the New World., 1982; Murray, Janice Weston; 2 (Box 8)
  - Concors: the new lineale., 1982; Ulagay, Abe (Box 29)
  - Trends in American graphic design: 1930-1955., 1982; Wild, Lorraine Yvonne Elizabeth (Box 8)
  - Icons and glamour., 1983; Apikos, Stacy (Box 8)
  - Paper: functional and aesthetic possibilities., 1983; Chu, Irene H. (Box 24)
  - Seal design in China: 1300 B.C. to the present., 1983; Chung, Fani (Box 8)